Data Engineer

Core Skill:

Data Engineer

Industry Verticals:

Banking Capital Markets Asset Wealth Management Insurance Media

Programming Languages:

Python SPARK SQL Java

Databases:

PostgreSQL SQLite

Tools & Techniques:

Docker GCP GitHub Kubernetes

Summary:

I am a highly resilient and committed data engineer with more than 4 years of working on developing and deploying models and pipelines for several companies. I have worked mainly on taking into cloud onpremises solutions across different platforms (Airflow, Spark, and Docker), mainly using Python as a central language. Excellent analytical problem-solving skills, team player, and goal-oriented engineer. As a complement, I am an undergraduate and graduate-level lecturer, with strong academic background.

Qualifications:

Educational Background:

Master of Science in Finance, Universidad EAFIT, 2021
Bachelor of Engineering, Civil Engineering, Universidad EIA, 2018

Certifications:

Data Science For All, Correlation One, 2021 Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera, 2020

Spoken Languages:

English, B2+ German, A2+ Spanish, Native

Soft Skills:

Hardworking Autonomy Empaty

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Industry sector: Finance

Senior Quantitative Analyst

2021-04-12 - 2022-12-09

Project descriptions:

Development and deployment of several strategists based on quantitative and AI to measure risk and flow of portfolios.

Currently researching causal AI to measure risk exposure on several pension funds. (Python, SQL and Pyspark)

Responsibilities:

Data Engineering and Modeling Analysis on financial market data (Python, SQL). Cloud development on portfolio valuation and risk measure (GCP, BigQuery, DataProc, Google Kubernetes Engine).

Programming Languages:

Python, SQL, SPARK

Tools & Techniques:

Testing:

Industry sector: Finance

Data Scientist and Data Engineer

2020-10-01 - 2021-04-09

Project descriptions:

"Time-series modeling to forecast the number and location of loan placements, in partnership with one of the largest banks in Colombia. (Python and SQL) "Credit card

Responsibilities:

Development and deployment of analytic solutions across different fields, as there are among.

customer classification based		
on transactional history to detect		
anomalies and possible		
disagreements between the		
customers and the bank.		
(Python, SQL, and		
Pyspark/Databricks)		
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:
Python, SQL, SPARK		